commbank.com.au 2007-06-26

# Commonwealth Bank Group - Security and Privacy

| **Tips On Protecting Your Financial Security**  
---  
  
The Commonwealth Bank is committed to protecting the financial security of its customers. We continue to invest in security that protects you, your name and your money. However, the best line of defence begins with you. For [tips](http://about.commbank.com.au/group_display/0,1922,NI2607%255FCH2607,00.html) on how you can help protect yourself against fraud, go to [Fraud & Security](http://about.commbank.com.au/group_display/0,1922,NI2607%255FCH2607,00.html).  
  
**Commonwealth Bank Group Privacy Policy Statement**  
  
The Commonwealth Bank Group's ("the Group") Privacy Policy Statement provides information on the Group's privacy and information handling practices. Click here to read the statement or download the pdf (120kb).

**Commonwealth Bank Group Online Privacy Statement**

This statement applies to your use of the web sites of the Commonwealth Bank Group (referred to as 'the Group'). This includes utilising any of the Group's facilities via the web sites. 

Information technology continues to present new and exciting opportunities. However, many people are concerned about how their personal information will be used. We recognise that our users may have concerns about their privacy and confidentiality whilst online. We are committed to ensuring the privacy and security of our users whilst using our web sites. 

In addition to the provisions of the Group's Privacy Policy Statement, there may also be specific and additional privacy provisions that apply to certain sections of the Group members' web sites. Because those specific and additional provisions also relate to your privacy protection, you should review them wherever they are accessible by you on the web sites. 

**The information outlined below is extracted from the Commonwealth Bank Group's Privacy Policy Statement and relates specifically to online use.**

Collection of information via web site activity  
Online security  
Cookies  
Web Site Advertising  
Links to other web sites  
Contact us about privacy  
  
**Collection of information via web site activity**

For statistical purposes we collect information on web site activity (such as the number of users who visit the web site, the date and time of visits, the number of pages viewed, navigation patterns, what country and systems users have used to access the site and, when entering our web site from another web site, the address of that web site) through the use of 'cookies'. This information on its own does not identify an individual but it does provide us with statistics that we can use to analyse and improve our web sites.  
  
**Online Security**

We are committed to keeping secure the personal information you provide to us. We take all reasonable precautions to protect the personal information we hold about you from misuse and loss and from unauthorised access, modification or disclosure.

We have a range of practices and policies in place to provide a robust security environment. We ensure the on-going adequacy of these measures by regularly reviewing them.

Our online security measures include, but are not limited to:

  * encrypting data sent from your computer to our systems during Internet transactions and customer access codes transmitted across networks;
  * employing firewalls, intrusion detection systems and virus scanning tools to protect against unauthorised persons and viruses from entering our systems; and
  * using dedicated secure networks or encryption when we transmit electronic data for purposes of outsourcing.
  * monitoring all email traffic.

**Cookies**

A 'cookie' is a packet of information that allows the server (the computer that houses the web site) to identify and interact more effectively with your computer.

When you use one of our web sites, we send you a cookie that gives you a unique identification number. A different identification number is sent each time you use our web sites. Cookies do not identify individual users, although they do identify a user's browser type and your Internet Service Provider (ISP).

You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is sent. Please refer to your browser instructions or help screens to learn more about these functions. If you reject all cookies, you may not be able to use our web sites.  
  
**Web Site Advertising**

To evaluate the effectiveness of our web site advertising, we may use third parties to collect statistical data. No personal data will be collected on these occasions.  
  
**Links to other web sites**

Our web sites may contain links to non-Commonwealth Bank Group web sites. Whilst such links are provided for your convenience, you should be aware that the information handling practices of the linked web sites might not be the same as ours.  
  
**Contact us about privacy**

If you have any questions or would like further information about our privacy and information handling practices, please contact us by:

  * e-mail at [CustomerRelations@cba.com.au](mailto:CustomerRelations@cba.com.au)
  * telephone **1800 805 605*** , or
  * writing to the address below:

Privacy Officer  
Customer Relations  
Commonwealth Bank Group  
Reply Paid 41  
Sydney NSW 2001

* A free call unless made from a mobile phone, which will be charged at the applicable mobile rate.
